<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>django on Chase Sawyer</title>
    <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in django on Chase Sawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 09:11:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chasesawyer.dev/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Maintenance App</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/07/car-maintenance-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 09:11:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/07/car-maintenance-app/</guid>
      <description>New app in progress! Hopefully it won&#39;t take months to complete. Should be pretty simple. Especially since this app is going to be primarily for me - and I&#39;m not going to worry too too much about the UI elements. Thinking this is going to be primarily a django based app with templates and model-based views like the keys app.
Current State: Developing database models
Purpose Provide myself and whoever wants it a place to track their car maintenance, and to make sure that they know when the next scheduled service for a particular maintenance item is due.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Infrastructure Project</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/05/docker-infrastructure-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 10:41:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/05/docker-infrastructure-project/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m building a web infrastructure project that&#39;s based around the project verbose-equals-true (referred to as VET from now on), which sets out to create a set of services to support modern web apps, using several Docker based images to collect everything into separate concerns. I like the philosophy behind the project, and it looks well thought out, however, as things are always changing in this landscape and nobody has the same development environment, there&#39;s always going to be stumbling blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining Older Django and Python Projects</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/02/maintaining-older-django-and-python-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 09:26:35 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/02/maintaining-older-django-and-python-projects/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on the backend for a project that I&#39;ve written about {{previously&amp;ndash;link}}. The established tools server that will be supporting my new React frontend app(s) will be using a backend built on Python 2.7 and Django 1.11, and thus I&#39;ve had to remember how to get a development environment set up that will appropriately support the project running locally on my machine. I have a personal site that runs on the same version of Django, but with Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KeysApp</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</guid>
      <description>The Keys App was my first major project that sought to solve a problem with managing key checkouts without requiring a cumbersome customer database / sign up form. This would target an institution that mostly catered to internal customers, such as a university&#39;s AV department and it&#39;s instructors. It largely replicates a paper-form-based system, with an added layer of data validation and control (emails, phone numbers must be in a valid format; keys can only be returned by their original owners; keys can&#39;t be checked out twice; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>