<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Update on Chase Sawyer</title>
    <link>https://shadowimmage.github.io/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Update on Chase Sawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 20:51:48 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shadowimmage.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Static Site with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2018-05-09-new-static-site-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 20:51:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2018-05-09-new-static-site-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Built a new site, leaving Jekyll for Hugo, for my github.io page.
Changes Moved all my old Jekyll files to a new subdirectory in order to maintain access to the old code and posts, and then transition all the content over to the main Hugo site as settings come together. One major advantage of Hugo is that the build process is super fast, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at how to integrate CircleCI with Hugo builds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Tk UI Notes, Project Update</title>
      <link>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2017-06-21-python-tk-iu-notes-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2017-06-21-python-tk-iu-notes-project-update/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been making a lot of progress on the python-LEDSerialController project. There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot to learn about how to run the original command line script with a GUI frontend. I chose to use Tk since it&amp;rsquo;s baked into Python already, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to configure to get it working. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look nearly as nice as something that would come out of using a more advanced UI toolkit, but it&amp;rsquo;s also had a lower bar to entry, despite some drawbacks with Tk&amp;rsquo;s documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Jekyll and Getting Started with Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2017-05-25-learning-jekyll-and-getting-started-with-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://shadowimmage.github.io/post/2017-05-25-learning-jekyll-and-getting-started-with-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>First Post!
Learning how to set up Jekyll on GitHub Pages is actually a little harder than I was expecting from the outset. Mostly because most of the things that you need to set up Jekyll for local development, and a lot of the things that come prepackaged with it aren&amp;rsquo;t actually necessary for running it on GitHub Pages.
Here is the Gemfile content for this page when I first started and got things working:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>