<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Chase Sawyer</title>
    <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Chase Sawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:06:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chasesawyer.dev/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTApp</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/rttapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:06:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/rttapp/</guid>
      <description>Repair Task Tracker RTT is a full stack app that addresses the needs of a computer hardware management process, allowing the tracking and resolution of issues/problems with the hardware, as well as the configuration and components of each major hardware item. RTT is meant to be a back-of-house tool, replacing paper tickets and spreadsheets. The goal of this project was to implement a GraphQL app, with useful data, allowing a seamless user experience as they operate through the app, and data is downloaded and uploaded in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KeysApp</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</guid>
      <description>The Keys App was my first major project that sought to solve a problem with managing key checkouts without requiring a cumbersome customer database / sign up form. This would target an institution that mostly catered to internal customers, such as a university&amp;rsquo;s AV department and it&amp;rsquo;s instructors. It largely replicates a paper-form-based system, with an added layer of data validation and control (emails, phone numbers must be in a valid format; keys can only be returned by their original owners; keys can&amp;rsquo;t be checked out twice; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SlackR25Bot - UW</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/slackr25bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 21:24:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/slackr25bot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was built for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cte.uw.edu/wordpress/&#34;&gt;Classroom Technologies &amp;amp; Events&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Collector - UW</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/dustcollector/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/dustcollector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a hammer drill that has a vacuum collector attachment, and we wanted a collector that could use different kinds of filters. I took the existing dust collector and designed an exact replacement that would take any kind of 3M respirator filter as the filter element. This allows using different kinds of filters and for the filters to be replaced. The parts involved were manually reverse-engineered on paper with the device and a set of good digital calipers. The replacement parts were designed in Autodesk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/overview&#34;&gt;Fusion360&lt;/a&gt; and 3D printed on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prusa3d.com/&#34;&gt;Prusa&lt;/a&gt; i3 MK2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>