<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heroku on Chase Sawyer</title>
    <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/tags/heroku/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Heroku on Chase Sawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 11:51:59 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chasesawyer.dev/tags/heroku/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google .dev Domains, GitHub Pages, and Heroku Apps</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/03/google-.dev-domains-github-pages-and-heroku-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 11:51:59 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/post/2019/03/google-.dev-domains-github-pages-and-heroku-apps/</guid>
      <description>At the end of February 2019, Google released general access to the .dev top level domain. I had heard about this happening about a year ago, and am now the happy owner of two .dev domains! One of these is chasesawyer.dev and will soon be the new home of this site!
But how to get it set up? When you buy a domain name, nothing is really set up for them - going to those addresses doesn&amp;rsquo;t point to anything Firefox and Google will just say &amp;ldquo;Server not found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTApp</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/rttapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:06:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/rttapp/</guid>
      <description>Repair Task Tracker RTT is a full stack app that addresses the needs of a computer hardware management process, allowing the tracking and resolution of issues/problems with the hardware, as well as the configuration and components of each major hardware item. RTT is meant to be a back-of-house tool, replacing paper tickets and spreadsheets. The goal of this project was to implement a GraphQL app, with useful data, allowing a seamless user experience as they operate through the app, and data is downloaded and uploaded in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KeysApp</title>
      <link>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>shadowimmage@gmail.com (Chase Sawyer)</author>
      <guid>https://chasesawyer.dev/project/keysapp/</guid>
      <description>The Keys App was my first major project that sought to solve a problem with managing key checkouts without requiring a cumbersome customer database / sign up form. This would target an institution that mostly catered to internal customers, such as a university&amp;rsquo;s AV department and it&amp;rsquo;s instructors. It largely replicates a paper-form-based system, with an added layer of data validation and control (emails, phone numbers must be in a valid format; keys can only be returned by their original owners; keys can&amp;rsquo;t be checked out twice; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>